RH

## Robert Heeter

### **Professional Summary**

Serviced-focused Manager dedicated to giving every customer positive experiences to promote loyalty and repeat business. Orchestrate optimal resource utilization to handle expected operational needs. Sales leader with sound judgment, good planning abilities and interpersonal communication strengths. Proficient Kitchen Manger driven to source the best ingredients at the best price and produce the highest quality, most efficient food service. Talented leader offering over 8 years of experience in preparing and serving diverse foods. Motivates employees to exceed customer expectations in high-volume settings while maintaining strong quality and effective cost controls. Service-oriented with good multitasking, safety management and decision-making skills.

Work History

#### Eleven Fifty Academy - Student

Indianapolis, IN

09/2020 - Current

Enrolled as a student at Eleven Fifty Academy, I have learned to use HTML5, CSS3, and javaScript to create visually pleasing web pages. The challenges Eleven Fifty Academy placed before me have helped me to develop new ways of thinking through problems that I have not always thought about.

#### Pier 48 - General Manager

Indianapolis, IN

10/2019 - 03/2020

- Developed strong working relationships with management and hourly team members through effective scheduling and communication skills.
- Worked with our Executive Chef to resolve menu problems, improve operations and provide exceptional customer service.
- Negotiated agreements between employees to clarify misunderstood directions and resolve conflicts affecting performance.
- Created a Pre-Shift board to inform all team members are aware of any changes in the restaurant.
- Assisted in kitchen inventory as well as bar inventory

rheeter28@gmail.com **H:** (317) 201-4886 Indianapolis, IN 46250

#### Skills

- Client Account Management
- Cross-Functional Team Management
- Scheduling
- Employee Training
- Sanitation
- Cooking
- Kitchen staff coordination
- Cost controls
- Staff Management
- Food preparation and safety
- Order delivery practices
- Motivational style

#### **Education**

08/2009

**Sullivan University** 

Louisville, KY

Associate of Arts: Culinary Arts

# Greenwood, IN 02/2019 - 09/2019

- Managed opening and closing procedures and recommended changes to enhance efficiency of daily activities.
- Assessed job applications and made hiring recommendations to bring in top candidates for key vacancies.
- Monitored employee performance and developed improvement plans.
- Coached team on effective upselling and cross-selling methods.
- Monitored cash intake and deposit records, increasing accuracy and reducing discrepancies.
- Checked prices and calculated totals for accurate invoice processing.
- Performed data entry and ensured completion of proper paperwork.
- Upheld optimal staff and customer protections by monitoring food handling, cleaning and sanitation protocols.
- Prepared food items to meet recipes, portioning, cooking and waste control guidelines.

#### Scottys Brewhouse - Kitchen Manager/Bar Manager

Indianapolis, IN

04/2011 - 01/2018

- Hired, trained and managed all kitchen staff, including employee development, issuing disciplinary action and conducting performance reviews.
- Scheduled and received food and beverage deliveries, adhering to food cost and budget.
- Continuously evaluated business operations to effectively align workflows for optimal area coverage and customer satisfaction.
- Spearheaded regular maintenance and repair operations to keep building and equipment in peak condition.
- Maintained kitchen cleanliness and sanitation through correct procedures and scheduled cleaning of surfaces and equipment.
- Inspected kitchens to observe food preparation quality and service, food appearance and cleanliness of production and service areas.
- Trained staff on proper cooking procedures as well as safety regulations and productivity strategies.
- Motivated staff to perform at peak efficiency and quality.
- Delivered in-depth training to workers in food preparation and customer-facing roles to promote strong team performance.
- Polished glassware, bussed tables and removed debris to keep customer areas fresh and clean.
- Kept alcoholic beverages well-stocked and organized to meet expected demands.
- Consulted with managers to organize special events and promotions such as trivia nights to bring in new customers.
- Maintained secure cash drawers, promptly resolving discrepancies for accuracy.
- Handled escalated customer concerns with speed and knowledgeable support to achieve optimal satisfaction and maintain long-term loyalty.
- Reduced labor costs by improving employee schedules and workflows

to capitalize on individual strengths and better meet forecasted customer demands.	